Vasileios Trikalinos

Kronenstrasse 37, 8006, Zurich, Switzerland 0041 798895459 billtrik@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am a **software engineer** with experience in **web development** whose main field of expertise is in **JavaScript** and with a constant focus on **performance**.

My experiences vary from creating web sites, reusable components and fully featured rich user interfaces, to being a system administrator as well as to design and implement complex architectures.

I really enjoy using the latest web technologies and always welcome the opportunity to learn something new.

SKILLS/TECHNOLOGIES

Front-end: JavaScript/ES6/ES7, React, Redux, Immutable.js, Backbone.js, Marionette.js, CoffeeScript,

jQuery, SCSS, Require.js, Browserify, Babel, Grunt, Gulp

Back-end: Ruby On Rails, Ruby, node.js, hapi.js, Laravel, PHP, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL

(PostGIS), redis, bash

Other Languages: C, C++, Java (university level)

Methodologies: Scrum, Kanban, TDD

Testing: Teaspoon, Enzyme, Karma.js, intern.js, Mocha, Chai.js, Sinon.js, Zombie.js, CasperJS,

Web Communications: XHR, JSONP, XDomain, REST APIs, WebSockets

Other: git, Phonegap/Cordova, Photoshop

OS of preference: OSX

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior JavaScript Software Engineer

10/2016 - Onwards

R3PI (Zurich)

 Implementation of micro services on node.js using a proprietary framework build on top of hapi.js

Front End Software Engineer

11/2014 - 8/2016

Workable.gr (Athens)

- Supported and implemented new features for main product as well as for its web-app counterpart, using (and mixing) React/Redux, backbone.js and marionette.js
- Worked with the **testing** workflow performance enhancements, automations. Helped to create **e2e testing suite** with supporting for **touch** gestures for the mobile version of the app, and to bootstrap our **React/Redux** testing setup
- OS work on a backbone extension providing mutex like functionality on model operations, on a lodash like library for Immutable.js, and also a benchmarking testbed project to ease out local js perf testing.

Javascript Software Engineer

10/2011 - 10/2014

skroutz.gr (Athens)

- **Skroutz analytics**: X-Domain tracking platform that tracks and reports data inside affiliated sites. Designed and implemented the Javascript client. Vanilla Javascript, X-Domain session tracking, X-Domain communications
- Rewrote the whole JS codebase using Coffescript, AMD modules and Require.js. Also created reusable components and plugins
- Chrome extension that consumes the REST API of the site. Implemented the OAuth2 dance
- Inception, design and implementation of JS continuous integration testing platform, using Testswarm and Jenkins
 - Implemented some jQuery plugins with most notable the Selectorablium.js project
- Widgets and widget-loading library that implemented JSONP and Cross-browser events handling

Full Stack Software Engineer

02/2011 - 09/2011

Generation-y.gr (Athens)

- Created a number of web-sites from the .PSD up
- HTML, CSS, Javascript and Ruby On Rails development

Software Engineer / System Administrator

02/2010 - 01/2011

Mindradio.gr (Athens)

- **Dedications**: Web-app implementing a dedications system. Backend that provides playlist like auditing of submissions, integration with existing Icecast scheduling mechanism. Client that integrates with Facebook API and provides audio recording
- HTML, CSS, Javascript and PHP development for the company sites and the admin interfaces
- · Unix daemon creation that monitors changes in files and updates database accordingly
- · Web-based File Manager

System Administrator

01/2005 - 06/2005

Support Department, Computer Science Department, University of Ioannina

- Maintenance and support
- · Accounts management
- System Administration (BSD, Solaris)

Software Engineer

2010 - Onwards

Freelancer

- Created two Phonegap apps:
 - Andoid and iOS apps for <u>welcomepickups.com</u> using **framework7**, backbone.js and marionette.js
 - Created an e-book reader featuring bookmarking on paragraph level and search
- Created a number of **responsive web-sites** using the **Laravel** PHP framework
 - o http://www.max-e-mize.co.uk
 - o http://www.petrinonaxos.gr
 - http://www.evrofarma.gr
- Created a custom ERP solution using PHP
- Personal project tracking web-app using the Ruby On Rails framework
- RubyOnRails based website to provide sensible cinema filtering using backbone.js and marionette.js. Implemented parser for data retrieval using node.js

OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS

PROFILES

- <u>github.com/skroutz/analytics.js</u>
- github.com/skroutz/selectorablium
- npmjs.com/package/karma-fixture
- npmjs.com/package/simple-benchmarkjs-runner
 npmjs.com/package/generator-benchmarkjs-runner
- github.com/billtrik
- stackoverflow.com/users/659610/basiloungas
- linkedin.com/pub/bill-trikalinos/a/85b/1ba

EDUCATION

BSc in Computer Science, University of Ioannina

2013

Thesis: "Alternative web services for online distribution of digital images"

Performance and scaling comparison between the blocking resource per request model of

Apache/PHP and the asynchronous non blocking model of node.js.

Courses:

- Web Development (Javascript, PHP, jsp-servlets, XML)
- Object Oriented Design Principles (Single Responsibility Principle (SRP), Liskov Substitution Principle (LSP), Low Coupling Principle (LCP), Dependency Inversion Principle (DIP), Open-Closed Principle (OCP), Interface Segregation Principle)
- Parallel Processing (MPI, OPENMP)
- Network Programming (BSD Sockets)
- Computer Systems Security (Buffer overflows, Man-in-the-middle attack)

LANGUAGES

- **English** Cambridge Proficiency degree
- Greek Native

${\tt INTERESTS}$

Motorcycles, Gaming, Music, Cinema, CrossFit, Martial Arts, Travelling